# Daniel Duclos-Cavalcanti

# Computer Engineer – English, German, & Portuguese

516-912-7975 | New York, NY | U.S. Citizen | me@duclos.dev | www.duclos.dev | linkedin | github

#### Summary

Creative thinker and problem-solver with a masters and bachelors in traditional german electrical engineering. Today, I am in New York, collaborating on exciting research with Dr.Sivaraman (NYU) that envisions a financial exchange on the cloud.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, Python, Golang, Rust, Bash, Lua, VHDL, Tcl, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Tools: Terraform, Docker, Packer, AWS, Google Cloud (GCP), Git, Unix Shell, Makefile, CMake, Linux, Jenkins, Vim Technologies: Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, Machine Learning, TCP, UDP, IP, FPGA, RTOS, IoT, HPC

Frameworks: ZeroMQ, DPDK, Tensorflow, TFLite, Numpy, Pandas, OpenMPI, OpenMP Certificates: UCSD: Data Structures Fundamentals, UT Austin: Embedded Systems - uC I/O

## EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Jul 2022 – Oct 2022

TU Munich

Molabo GmbH

Munich, Germany

- Generated reports to establish a Design-Space Exploration framework to guide ML model deployments.
- Evaluated and compared the performance of various Machine Learning models across GPUs, CPUs and TPUs.
- Analyzed USB traffic through PyShark between the host and externally added TPUs.

## Embedded Engineer Intern

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Ottobrunn, Germany

- Developed tooling for state simulations of their electric motor via Linux's virtual CAN interface and mock APIs.
- Added unit-tests and code coverage to safety critical features of their motor drive embedded controller.
- Automated build and testing workflows via Jenkins and CMake for a team of over 10 engineers.

# Tutor - Embedded Systems Programming Lab

Apr 2021 – Aug 2021

TU Munich

Munich, Germany

• Supervised and aided 20+ students on their final embedded FreeRTOS laboratory projects in C.

## PROJECTS

Cloud TreeFinder | GCP, Terraform, Python, C++, Distributed Systems, ZMQ, Protobufs March 2024 - Present

- Launches a cloud cluster and from it's pool of N VMs forms an optimal multicast tree of depth D and fanout F.
- Deploys probe jobs on randomly selected node subsets, collecting and processing resulting reports (JSON).
- Applies a developed heuristic from the collected data to select nodes in the tree layer by layer.
- Uses terraform to manage cloud state, ZMQ for node communication and Protobufs for data (de)-serialization.

#### **Open-MPI Value Iteration** | *C++*, *Multi-Threaded*, *HPC*

Sept 2021 – Feb 2022

• Asynchronous value iteration model to distribute workload on an HPC cluster.

#### **Publications**

# Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud | (Paper)

Jan 24 – Present

- Novel cloud hosted financial exchange achieving low latency multicast service for up to 1000 market participants.
- Achieves better scalability and around 50% lower latency than the multicast service provided by AWS.
- Used kernel-bypass techniques (DPDK) to achieve ultra-low latency at up to 35K multicast packet rate.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### New York University: Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

 $Sept\ 2023-May\ 2024$ 

Computer Science - Visiting Non-Degree Graduate Student

GPA 4.0

- Co-Authored Publication: Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud
- Related Coursework: Operating Systems, Technologies in Finance

#### **Technical University of Munich**

Oct 2020 - **Sept 2024** 

M.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

- M.Sc. Thesis: VM Selection Heuristic for Multicast Overlay Trees in the Cloud
- Related Coursework: Machine Learning Methods and Tools, Embedded Design for Machine Learning, Chips Multicore Processors, Secure SoCs for IoT, High Performance Computing for Machine Intelligence

## Technical University of Munich

Oct 2016 - Sept 2020

B.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering